ANNE-LAURE FRÉANT

Technical writer

BACKGROUND

With 10 years of experience in the digital industry, for innovative startup in Canada as well as french state-level institutions (ministers & Prime Minister Services), I have gained a wide set of skills as a technical writer, content writer and UX writer. I am looking for a position within an ambitious company or startup to grow for the next years, preferably in innovative environment where autonomy and continuous-learning are valued.

SKILLS

- Technical writing: software and API documentation and guides
- Knowledge base, Confluence
- Markdown, HTML 5, CSS
- Basic knowledge of Javascript
- · Github, GitPages
- CMS (Wordpress)
- Static sites (Jekyll, Docusaurus)
- · Agile methods
- JIRA, Notion, Trello, Slack
- Google suite,
- Adobe Illustrator (for diagrams)
- Suite Office
- · Research and technology watch
- Bilingual english-french (TEFL certification for Teaching English as a Foreign Language); TOEIC score 975

CERTIFICATES

- "API Technical Writing" (Udemy course), to obtained in 2022
- -"Contentsquare Expert" (certification obtained in 2022)

CONTACT

Cell: +33 7 81 85 42 73

Email: annelaure.freant@gmail.com

WORK EXPERIENCE

Technical writer & Product Knowledge Manager (Sept. 2022-Jan. 2023) Paris and remote - Contentsquare (full time contract)

I joined the Knowledge Management Team and was in charge of a part of the product's internal knowledge base. I updated and wrote the documentation (product foundations: APIs, data pipeline, back-office), and managed internal release communications (Slack and emails).

Freelance technical writer and translator (June 2021 - Aug. 2022) Remote from France

• Conducting technical writing projects for a variety of customers (Programming Historian, CNAM...), translating programming tutorials, updating software documentation, using mostly Github, HTML and Markdown files.

Student (gap year) (Sept. 2020 - June 2021)

Post-master degree at the School of Public Affairs, Sciencespo Paris

• Following courses about digital ethics, data privacy and public algorithms.

Data editor (Full time contract. Jan. 2020 - Aug. 2020)

Etalab, French Prime Minister Services (Paris)

Within the team in charge of the open data platform data.gouv.fr, I worked as a technical writer on both data.gouv.fr documentation and content pages of the platform itself (datasets description and listing). Part of the job also involved some editorial project management (editorial planning, social media).

Technical & UX writer (Consultant from Jan. 2016 to Dec. 2020)

French Ministry of Foreign Affairs (Paris)

• As the founder of a website about reentry in France (retourenfrance.fr), I became the UX writer and content writer for the creation of an online public service. I designed the matrix of rules and conditions (which content to display according to the end user's administrative situation) and managed the editorial maintenance during 4 years, collaborating with content experts from various french administrations.

Technical Content Team Lead (full time contract, Jan. 2011 - Dec. 2014) Hopper.com (Montreal & Boston)

• I entered the company as a part-time data entry specialist. After 6 months I was offered to take the lead of the content team (reporting directly to CEO), and a year later I was offered to take the lead of Hopper's research and innovation blog as an editorial project manager.

Research & Teaching assistant (full time contract, 2008-2011)

Geography department, University of Quebec in Montreal (Montreal)

• Teaching and assisting the Pr. M. Bédard with research seminars and lectures.

EDUCATION

Sciencespo Paris - Post-Master degree, School of Public Affairs Sept. 2020 - June 2021

University of Quebec in Montreal (UQAM)- Master degree in Geography

Sept. 2006 - June 2008